<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>ymca1990batch</title>
    <link href="https://ymca1990.github.io/ymca-pages/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://ymca1990.github.io/ymca-pages" />
    <updated>2020-05-26T21:32:46+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>A YMCAian</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://ymca1990.github.io/ymca-pages</id>

    <entry>
        <title>YMCA 1990 Batch - Life Journeys</title>
        <author>
            <name>A YMCAian</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ymca1990.github.io/ymca-pages/ymca-1990-batch.html"/>
        <id>https://ymca1990.github.io/ymca-pages/ymca-1990-batch.html</id>

        <updated>2020-05-23T21:23:53+05:30</updated>
            <summary></summary>
        <content></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Mohit Sahni</title>
        <author>
            <name>A YMCAian</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://ymca1990.github.io/ymca-pages/mohit-sahni.html"/>
        <id>https://ymca1990.github.io/ymca-pages/mohit-sahni.html</id>

        <updated>2020-05-26T21:27:42+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://ymca1990.github.io/ymca-pages/media/posts/3/Mohit.jpg" alt="" />
                    My journey since YMCA days....... Career journey so far Some of you might be aware that I got selected for CMC through campus selection. I worked in CMC for 12 long years before I moved to Wipro in Bangalore (2006) and worked for 14 months. Finally joined&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://ymca1990.github.io/ymca-pages/media/posts/3/Mohit.jpg" alt="" />
                <div>My journey since YMCA days.......</div>
<div> </div>
<div><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Career journey so far</span></strong></div>
<div> </div>
<div>Some of you might be aware that I got selected for CMC through campus selection. I worked in CMC for 12 long years before I moved to Wipro in Bangalore (2006) and worked for 14 months. Finally joined Accenture and today I've completed 12 years in Accenture.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>CMC remains as "The best" company I worked for and this is not just because it was the first job.  Best part about CMC was its working culture and human connections we experienced as employees. We used to be thrown into the sea without any training and challenged to learn on our own. I got to work on variety of systems including Mainframes and for diverse clients. During this tenure I was posted in Jodhpur for 3.5 years and handled operations for west Rajasthan. I can recollect best moments of this period when I alongwith my better half visited Udaipur and Pari took great care of us. My wife still remembers the hospitality shown by my dear friend.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Few things went wrong with start of new century and after being sold for peanuts to TCS in 2001, things changed dramatically (for worst) for CMC. Still i continued working there for few more years and reluctantanly decided to make a move out in 2006.</div>
<div>Key takeaways from CMC tenure:</div>
<div>I leveraged learning opportunities(on the job) and  gained invaluable E2E project management experience. Also I made some great friends in CMC and among clients who continue to be integral part of my life.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Wipro was a short stint (I moved to Bangalore for this job) and my role remained focused on setting up Project Management office for Infrastructure Services. Yes, I met few great leaders who shaped my thought process, especially about global IT world.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Accenture tenure since 2008 has been good and I have worked in different capacities (delivery excellence, capability, business enablement) in last 10+ years however people management and project delivey remains the core. </div>
<div>Summing up my career journey, I have been lucky and blessed in a way that I got variety of roles to play and I never had to chase professional growth (somehow I got more than what I deserved). Anyway at this stage of career, positions/levels seem unimportant and ability &amp; capacity to influence &amp; guide teams is the most significant motivation that takes me to office every day.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>By the way I enrolled for AMIE as almost everyone used to do in our times and didn't finish as almost everyone… I finally did BS degree from BITS Pilani in 2006. You expect a long distance course to be easy but boy, this was tougher than everything else...</div>
<div> </div>
<div><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>YMCA days</strong></span></div>
<div>Reflecting back on YMCA days after 25 years, it's a mixed feeling especially after visiting campus for reunion. It's natural to compare our (old) time vs current time and "Old is Gold" is again a natural reaction. However I strongly feel that we had seen better times of YMCA.</div>
<div>Taking a campus/hostel tour was like zooming back 25 years and reliving memories of an important phase of our life. Ragging period, Mandal protest, Freshers party, college trips, stupid fights, movie nights, sittng on bus roof for commute between Faridabad/Gurgaon, playing cards all nights… I can go on and on with the list and all of it has a common theme - spending time with friends (all of you rascals) and this is my most cherished memory of YMCA days.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Susheel posed a question in his original note - if YMCA education did help at all? I can say for myself - I live DIY (do it yourself) philosophy at home or office and YMCA education perhaps played a role in shaping that thought process.</div>
<div> </div>
<div><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>This WhatsApp Group</strong></span></div>
<div>You are the most irritating bunch of folks who love writing Hindi in English (which takes extra effort to read) but then you bring smile to my face, multiple times during the day. I have tried moving out of the group few times but then couple of kaminey friends(Mukesh, Pawan) don't leave you behind. And yes I do look forward to checking messages in this group.</div>
<div> </div>
<div><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Personal life</strong></span></div>
<div>I have been extremely fortunate in personal life. My spouse, Ruchi sacrificed her career and moved with me to Bangalore without hesitation. For her taking care of family was the top priority and this helped me in settling down at new place. She now works as a teacher, bit unfair considering her educational background however she expresses no regrets. My twin sons of 18 years will go to college this year and so far they have given no reason to complain about. They are doing reasonbly ok in studies and hopefully this trend continues. Im extremely blessed to have my mother with me. She is always a pillar of strength and my mentor/guide, especially during tough times.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>The defining moment of last 25 years or rather entire life for me - holding my new born babies for the first time!! Two nurses brought my twin sons from OT and i was like frozen for a minute and then started crying. Nurses waited patiently for me to stop crying and hold the babies which was a challenge anyway - can't hold both at the same time and which one to hold first ? I get goosebumps everytime i revisit this moment, just like now.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Life has its own way of balancing things and same year I lost my father. My father lived all his life serving railways and just after a year of retirement, lost his breath most peacefully at nowhere else but a railway station. Indebted to Railways however for arranging a special train to bring back my departed father to Gurgaon from Delhi Serai station.</div>
<div> </div>
<div><span style="text-decoration: underline;"><strong>Reflection on life at this stage</strong></span></div>
<div>I missed highlighting milestones in my life and this was deliberate. In my personal view, targeting goals and achieving milestones is overrated stuff. There are accomplishments in my career in terms of roles, positions i got however I consider them superficial (and myself plain lucky). For me the best moments have been when I was able to mentor/guide a person and help them reach their "Milestones". Also I feel deeply satisfied when I look back at the ever lasting relationships I have made over last 25 years.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>I will however mention a small accomplishment here. I gained 14 kg in just a year (2014) and my cholesterol jumped over 300. I took a path of being physically more active with cycling and did few thousands kms of cycling till around early 2017. Waking up at 4 and doing cycling for 60-70 kms at stretch became a habit and it brought me to weight range of 70-75 and cholesterol below 200. I took on running in 2017 and have done few half marathons since then. I wish to be more regular and hoping to run milege of 1500 kms in 2020. Diabetes and heart disease runs in my family and for me its critical to be active and healthy. Also I have picked up cooking of late and trying my hands mostly with Fish &amp; Chicken dishes over the weekend. I guess Im doing okay as my kids love the dishes I cook.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>A long read which surely tested your patience.</div>
<div> </div>
<div>Journey continues.....</div>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
